<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BioSamplePackages>
  <Package group="MIMARKS.survey">
    <Name>MIMARKS.survey.food-animal.6.0</Name>
    <DisplayName>MIMARKS: survey, food-animal and animal feed; version 6.0</DisplayName>
    <ShortName>MIMARKS Survey related</ShortName>
    <EnvPackage>food-animal</EnvPackage>
    <EnvPackageDisplay>food-animal and animal feed</EnvPackageDisplay>
    <NotAppropriateFor>wgs_single;wgs_batch;wgs_diploid</NotAppropriateFor>
    <Description>Use for any type of marker gene sequences, eg, 16S, 18S, 23S, 28S rRNA or COI obtained directly from the environment, without culturing or identification of the organisms. Organism must be a metagenome, where lineage starts with 
unclassified sequences and scientific name ends with 'metagenome'.</Description>
    <Example/>
    <TemplateHeader># This is a submission template for batch deposit of 'MIMARKS: survey, food-animal and animal feed; version 6.0' samples to the NCBI BioSample database (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/biosample/).&#13;
# Fields with an asterisk (*) are mandatory. Your submission will fail if any mandatory fields are not completed. If information is unavailable for any mandatory field, please enter 'not collected', 'not applicable' or 'missing' as appropriate.&#13;
# All other fields are optional. Leave optional fields empty if no information is available.&#13;
# You can add any number of custom fields to fully describe your BioSamples, simply include them in the table.&#13;
# CAUTION: Be aware that Excel may automatically apply formatting to your data. In particular, take care with dates, incrementing autofills and special characters like / or -. Doublecheck that your text file is accurate before uploading to BioSample.&#13;
# TO MAKE A SUBMISSION:&#13;
#     1. Complete the template table (typically in Excel, or another spreadsheet application)&#13;
#     2. Save the worksheet as a Text (Tab-delimited) file - use 'File, Save as, Save as type: Text (Tab-delimited)'&#13;
#     3. Upload the file on the 'Attributes' tab of the BioSample Submission Portal at https://submit.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/subs/biosample/.&#13;
#     4. If you have any questions, please contact us at biosamplehelp@ncbi.nlm.nih.gov.</TemplateHeader>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>collection site geographic feature</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>coll_site_geo_feat</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Text or terms that describe the geographic feature where the food sample was obtained by the researcher. This field encourages selected terms listed under the following ontologies: anthropogenic geographic feature (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ENVO_00000002), for example agricultural fairground [ENVO:01000986]; garden [ENVO:00000011} or any of its subclasses; market [ENVO:01000987]; water well [ENVO:01000002]; or human construction (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ENVO_00000070), e.g., grocery store [GENEPIO:0001020]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>collection date</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>collection_date</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>the date on which the sample was collected; date/time ranges are supported by providing two dates from among the supported value formats, delimited by a forward-slash character; collection times are supported by adding "T", then the hour and minute after the date, and must be in Coordinated Universal Time (UTC), otherwise known as "Zulu Time" (Z); supported formats include "DD-Mmm-YYYY", "Mmm-YYYY", "YYYY" or ISO 8601 standard "YYYY-mm-dd", "YYYY-mm", "YYYY-mm-ddThh:mm:ss"; e.g., 30-Oct-1990, Oct-1990, 1990, 1990-10-30, 1990-10,  21-Oct-1952/15-Feb-1953, 2015-10-11T17:53:03Z; valid non-ISO dates will be automatically transformed to ISO format</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{timestamp}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>broad-scale environmental context</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>env_broad_scale</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Add terms that identify the major environment type(s) where your sample was collected. Recommend subclasses of biome [ENVO:00000428]. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes e.g.:  mangrove biome [ENVO:01000181]|estuarine biome [ENVO:01000020]&#13;
</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>local-scale environmental context</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>env_local_scale</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Add terms that identify environmental entities having causal influences upon the entity at time of sampling, multiple terms can be separated by pipes, e.g.:  shoreline [ENVO:00000486]|intertidal zone [ENVO:00000316]&#13;
</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>environmental medium</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>env_medium</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Add terms that identify the material displaced by the entity at time of sampling. Recommend subclasses of environmental material [ENVO:00010483]. Multiple terms can be separated by pipes e.g.: estuarine water [ENVO:01000301]|estuarine mud [ENVO:00002160]&#13;
</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food product origin geographic location</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_origin</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A reference to a place on the Earth, by its name or by its geographical location that describes the origin of the food commodity, either in terms of its cultivation or production. This field encourages terms listed under geographic location (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GAZ_00000448), e.g., Thailand</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food production characteristics</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_prod_char</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Descriptors of the food production system such as wild caught, free-range, organic, free-range, industrial, dairy, beef</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food product type</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_product_type</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A food product type is a class of food products that is differentiated by its food composition (e.g., single- or multi-ingredient), processing and/or consumption characteristics. This does not include brand name products but it may include generic food dish categories. This field encourages terms under food product type (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON:03400361). For terms related to food product for an animal, consult food product for animal (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03309997). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the food type. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes, e.g., multi-component food product [FOODON:00002501]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>geographic location</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>geo_loc_name</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Geographical origin of the sample; use the appropriate name from this list http://www.insdc.org/documents/country-qualifier-vocabulary. Use a colon to separate the country or ocean from more detailed information about the location, eg "Canada: Vancouver" or "Germany: halfway down Zugspitze, Alps"</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}:{term}:{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>Interagency Food Safety Analytics Collaboration (IFSAC) category</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>ifsac_category</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The IFSAC food categorization scheme has five distinct levels to which foods can be assigned, depending upon the type of food. First, foods are assigned to one of four food groups (aquatic animals, land animals, plants, and other). Food groups include increasingly specific food categories; dairy, eggs, meat and poultry, and game are in the land animal food group, and the category meat and poultry is further subdivided into more specific categories of meat (beef, pork, other meat) and poultry (chicken, turkey, other poultry). Finally, foods are differentiated by differences in food processing (such as pasteurized fluid dairy products, unpasteurized fluid dairy products, pasteurized solid and semi-solid dairy products, and unpasteurized solid and semi-solid dairy products. An IFSAC food category chart is available from https://www.cdc.gov/foodsafety/ifsac/projects/food-categorization-scheme.html PMID: 28926300, e.g., Plants:Produce:Vegetables:Herbs:Dried Herbs</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>intended consumer</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>intended_consumer</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Food consumer type, human or animal, for which the food product is produced and marketed, e.g., human</Description>
      <Format type="select">
        <Description>human as food consumer | animal as food consumer | missing | not applicable | not collected | not provided | restricted access</Description>
        <Choice/>
        <Choice>human as food consumer</Choice>
        <Choice>animal as food consumer</Choice>
        <Choice>missing</Choice>
        <Choice>not applicable</Choice>
        <Choice>not collected</Choice>
        <Choice>not provided</Choice>
        <Choice>restricted access</Choice>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>latitude and longitude</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>lat_lon</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The geographical coordinates of the location where the sample was collected. Specify as degrees latitude and longitude in format "d[d.dddd] N|S d[dd.dddd] W|E", eg, 38.98 N 77.11 W</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {float}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="mandatory" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>purpose of sampling</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>purpose_of_sampling</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>the reason that the sample was collected, e.g., active surveillance in response to an outbreak, active surveillance not initiated by an outbreak, clinical trial, cluster investigation, environmental assessment, farm sample, field trial, for cause, industry internal investigation, market sample, passive surveillance, population based studies, research, research and development</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal antimicrobial duration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_am_dur</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The duration of time (days) that the antimicrobial was administered to the food animal</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {day}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal antimicrobial frequency</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_am_freq</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The frequency per day that the antimicrobial was adminstered to the food animal</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal antimicrobial route of administration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_am_route</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The route by which the antimicrobial is adminstered into the body of the food animal</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal antimicrobial intended use</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_am_use</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The prescribed intended use of or the condition treated by the antimicrobial given to the food animal by any route of administration</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal body condition</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_body_cond</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Body condition scoring is a production management tool used to evaluate overall health and nutritional needs of a food animal, e.g., normal, over conditioned, under conditioned</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal source diet</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_diet</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>If the isolate is from a food animal, the type of diet eaten by the food animal. Please list the main food staple and the setting, if appropriate. For a list of acceptable animal feed terms or categories, please see http://www.feedipedia.org. Multiple terms may apply and can be separated by pipes. Food product for animal covers foods intended for consumption by domesticated animals. Consult http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03309997. If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the food type. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes. If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the food product type</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>animal feeding equipment</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_feed_equip</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Description of the feeding equipment used for livestock. This field accepts terms listed under feed delivery (http://opendata.inra.fr/EOL/EOL_0001757). Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal source sex category</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>animal_sex</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The sex and reproductive status of the food animal, e.g., castrated female, castrated male, intact female, intact male</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>bacterial density</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>bacterial_density</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Number of bacteria in sample, as defined by bacteria density (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GENEPIO_0000043)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>collection method </Name>
      <HarmonizedName>collection_method</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Process used to collect the sample, e.g., bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food stored by consumer (storage duration)</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cons_food_stor_dur</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The storage duration of the food commodity by the consumer, prior to onset of illness or sample collection. Indicate the timepoint written in ISO 8601 format</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{timepoint}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food stored by consumer (storage temperature)</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cons_food_stor_temp</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Temperature at which food commodity was stored by the consumer, prior to onset of illness or sample collection</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}|{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>purchase date</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cons_purch_date</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The date a food product was purchased by consumer</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{timestamp}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>quantity purchased</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cons_qty_purchased</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The quantity of food purchased by consumer</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{integer} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>culture isolation date</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cult_isol_date</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A culture isolation date is a date-time entity marking the end of a process in which a sample yields a positive result for the target microbial analyte(s) in the form of an isolated colony or colonies, e.g., 5/24/2020</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>culture result</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cult_result</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Any result of a bacterial culture experiment reported as a binary assessment, e.g., absent, active, inactive, negative, no, present, positive, yes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>culture result organism</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cult_result_org</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Taxonomic information about the cultured organism(s)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>culture target microbial analyte</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>cult_target</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The target microbial analyte in terms of investigation scope. This field accepts terms under organism (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C14250). This field also accepts identification numbers from NCBI under https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/taxonomy</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>enrichment protocol</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>enrichment_protocol</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The microbiological workflow or protocol followed to test for the presence or enumeration of the target microbial analyte(s). Please provide a PubMed or DOI reference for published protocols</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{PMID}|{DOI}|{URL}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>experimental factor</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>experimental_factor</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Variable aspect of experimental design</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term|text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food additive</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_additive</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A substance or substances added to food to maintain or improve safety and freshness, to improve or maintain nutritional value, or improve taste, texture and appearance.  This field encourages terms listed under food additive (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03412972). Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes, but please consider limiting this list to the top 5 ingredients listed in order as on the food label.  See also, https://www.fda.gov/food/food-ingredients-packaging/overview-food-ingredients-additives-colors, e.g., xanthan gum [FOODON:03413321]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food contact surface</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_contact_surf</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The specific container or coating materials in direct contact with the food. Multiple values can be assigned.  This field encourages terms listed under food contact surface (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03500010), e.g., aluminum surface [FOODON:03500042]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food container or wrapping</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_contain_wrap</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Type of container or wrapping defined by the main container material, the container form, and the material of the liner lids or ends. Also type of container or wrapping by form; prefer description by material first, then by form. This field encourages terms listed under food container or wrapping (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03490100), e.g., bottle or jar [FOODON:03490203]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food cooking process</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_cooking_proc</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The transformation of raw food by the application of heat. This field encourages terms listed under food cooking (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03450002), e.g., food blanching [FOODON:03470175]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food distribution point geographic location</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_dis_point</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A reference to a place on the Earth, by its name or by its geographical location that refers to a distribution point along the food chain. This field accepts terms listed under geographic location (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GAZ_00000448). Reference: Adam Diamond, James Barham. Moving Food Along the Value Chain: Innovations in Regional Food Distribution. U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Agricultural Marketing Service. Washington, DC. March 2012. http://dx.doi.org/10.9752/MS045.03-2012</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}: {term}, {text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food distribution point geographic location (city)</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_dis_point_city</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A reference to a place on the Earth, by its name or by its geographical location that refers to a distribution point along the food chain. This field accepts terms listed under geographic location (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GAZ_00000448). Reference: Adam Diamond, James Barham. Moving Food Along the Value Chain: Innovations in Regional Food Distribution. U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Agricultural Marketing Service. Washington, DC. March 2012. http://dx.doi.org/10.9752/MS045.03-2012</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food ingredient</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_ingredient</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>In this field, please list individual ingredients for multi-component food [FOODON:00002501] and simple foods that is not captured in food_type. Please use terms that are present in FoodOn. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes, but please consider limiting this list to the top 5 ingredients listed in order as on the food label. See also, https://www.fda.gov/food/food-ingredients-packaging/overview-food-ingredients-additives-colors</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food package capacity</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_pack_capacity</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The maximum number of product units within a package</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food packing integrity</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_pack_integrity</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A term label and term id to describe the state of the packing material and text to explain the exact condition.  This field encourages terms listed under food packing medium integrity (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03530218), e.g., food packing medium compromised [FOODON:00002517]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food packing medium</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_pack_medium</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The medium in which the food is packed for preservation and handling or the medium surrounding homemade foods, e.g., peaches cooked in sugar syrup. The packing medium may provide a controlled environment for the food. It may also serve to improve palatability and consumer appeal. This includes edible packing media (e.g. fruit juice), gas other than air (e.g. carbon dioxide), vacuum packed, or packed with aerosol propellant. This field encourages terms under food packing medium (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03480020). Multiple terms may apply and can be separated by pipes, e.g., vacuum-packed [FOODON:03480027]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food preservation process</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_preserv_proc</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The methods contributing to the prevention or retardation of microbial, enzymatic or oxidative spoilage and thus to the extension of shelf life. This field encourages terms listed under food preservation process (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03470107), e.g., food fermentation [FOODON:00001304]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>material of contact prior to food packaging</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_prior_contact</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The material the food contacted (e.g., was processed in) prior to packaging. This field accepts terms listed under material of contact prior to food packaging (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03530077). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the material of contact prior to food packaging</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food product synonym</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_prod_synonym</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Other names by which the food product is known by (e.g., regional or non-English names), e.g., pinot gris</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food product by quality</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_product_qual</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Descriptors for describing food visually or via other senses, which is useful for tasks like food inspection where little prior knowledge of how the food came to be is available. Some terms like "food (frozen)" are both a quality descriptor and the output of a process. This field accepts terms listed under food product by quality (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_00002454)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food quality date</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_quality_date</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The date recommended for the use of the product while at peak quality, this date is not a reflection of safety unless used on infant formula this date is not a reflection of safety and is typically labeled on a food product as ""best if used by,"" best by,"" ""use by,"" or ""freeze by"", e.g., 5/24/2020</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food source</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_source</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Individual organism or category of organisms from which the food product or its major ingredient is derived, e.g., giant tiger prawn [FOODON:03412612]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food source age</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_source_age</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The age of the food source host organim. Depending on the type of host organism, age may be more appropriate to report in days, weeks, or years</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food traceability list category</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_trace_list</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The FDA is proposing to establish additional traceability recordkeeping requirements (beyond what is already required in existing regulations) for persons who manufacture, process, pack, or hold foods the Agency has designated for inclusion on the Food Traceability List. The Food Traceability List (FTL) identifies the foods for which the additional traceability records described in the proposed rule would be required. The term ""Food Traceability List"" (FTL) refers not only to the foods specifically listed (https://www.fda.gov/media/142303/download), but also to any foods that contain listed foods as ingredients, e.g., tropical tree fruits</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food shipping transportation method</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_trav_mode</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A descriptor for the method of movement of food commodity along the food distribution system. This field accepts terms listed under travel mode (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GENEPIO_0001064). If the proper descrptor is not listed please use text to describe the mode of travel. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food shipping transportation vehicle</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_trav_vehic</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A descriptor for the mobile machine which is used to transport food commodities along the food distribution system. This field accepts terms listed under vehicle (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ENVO_01000604). If the proper descrptor is not listed please use text to describe the mode of travel. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food treatment process</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>food_treat_proc</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Used to specifically characterize a food product based on the treatment or processes applied to the product or any indexed ingredient. The processes include adding, substituting or removing components or modifying the food or component, e.g., through fermentation. Multiple values can be assigned. This fields accepts terms listed under food treatment process (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03460111)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>Hazard Analysis Critical Control Points (HACCP) guide food safety term</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>haccp_term</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Hazard Analysis Critical Control Points (HACCP) food safety terms; This field accepts terms listed under HACCP guide food safety term (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03530221)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>antimicrobial name</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>host_am</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The class(es) or name(s) (generic or brand) of the antimicrobial(s) given to the food animal within the last 30 days, e.g., tetracycline [CHEBI:27902]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>food animal group size</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>host_group_size</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The number of food animals of the same species that are maintained together as a unit, i.e. a herd or flock, e.g., 80</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>animal housing system </Name>
      <HarmonizedName>host_housing</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Description of the housing system of the livestock. This field encourages terms listed under terrestrial management housing system (http://opendata.inra.fr/EOL/EOL_0001605), e.g., pen [EOL:0001902]</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional">
      <Name>isolation source</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>isolation_source</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Describes the physical, environmental and/or local geographical source of the biological sample from which the sample was derived.</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>None</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>lot number</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>lot_number</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A distinctive alpha-numeric identification code assigned by the manufacturer or distributor to a specific quantity of manufactured material or product within a batch. The submitter should provide lot number of the item followed by the item name for which the lot number was provided</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{integer}, {text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>microbiological culture medium</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>microb_cult_med</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A culture medium used to select for, grow, and maintain prokaryotic microorganisms. Can be in either liquid (broth) or solidified (e.g. with agar) forms. This field accepts terms listed under microbiological culture medium (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/MICRO_0000067). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the culture medium</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>miscellaneous parameter</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>misc_param</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>any other measurement performed or parameter collected, that is not listed here</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text};{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional">
      <Name>negative control type</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>neg_cont_type</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The substance or equipment used as a negative control in an investigation, e.g., distilled water, phosphate buffer, empty collection device, empty collection tube, DNA-free PCR mix, sterile swab, sterile syringe</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Environment">
      <Name>Omics Observatory ID</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>omics_observ_id</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A unique identifier of the omics-enabled observatory (or comparable time series) your data derives from. This identifier should be provided by the OMICON ontology; if you require a new identifier for your time series, contact the ontology's developers. Information is available here: https://github.com/GLOMICON/omicon. This field is only applicable to records which derive from an omics time-series or observatory.</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>organism count</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>organism_count</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>total count of any organism per gram or volume of sample,should include name of organism followed by count; can include multiple organism counts</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text};{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>part of plant or animal</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>part_plant_animal</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The anatomical part of the organism being involved in food production or consumption; e.g., a carrot is the root of the plant (root vegetable). This field accepts terms listed under part of plant or animal (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/FOODON_03420116)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>perturbation</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>perturbation</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>type of perturbation, e.g. chemical administration, physical disturbance, etc., coupled with time that perturbation occurred; can include multiple perturbation types</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text};{interval}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>pooling of DNA extracts</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>pool_dna_extracts</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>were multiple DNA extractions mixed? how many?</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{boolean};{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional">
      <Name>positive control type</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>pos_cont_type</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The substance, mixture, product, or apparatus used to verify that a process which is part of an investigation delivers a true positive
</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term} or {text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>relationship to oxygen</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>rel_to_oxygen</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Is this organism an aerobe, anaerobe? Please note that aerobic and anaerobic are valid descriptors for microbial environments, eg, aerobe, anaerobe, facultative, microaerophilic, microanaerobe, obligate aerobe, obligate anaerobe, missing, not applicable, not collected, not provided, restricted access</Description>
      <Format type="select">
        <Description>aerobe | anaerobe | facultative | microaerophilic | microanaerobe | obligate aerobe | obligate anaerobe | missing | not applicable | not collected | not provided | restricted access</Description>
        <Choice/>
        <Choice>aerobe</Choice>
        <Choice>anaerobe</Choice>
        <Choice>facultative</Choice>
        <Choice>microaerophilic</Choice>
        <Choice>microanaerobe</Choice>
        <Choice>obligate aerobe</Choice>
        <Choice>obligate anaerobe</Choice>
        <Choice>missing</Choice>
        <Choice>not applicable</Choice>
        <Choice>not collected</Choice>
        <Choice>not provided</Choice>
        <Choice>restricted access</Choice>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>repository</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>repository</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>the name of the institution where the sample or DNA extract is held or "sample not available" if the sample was used in its entirety for analysis or otherwise not retained</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description/>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>sample collection device or method</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_collect_device</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Method or device employed for collecting sample</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample collection method</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_collect_method</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The method employed for collecting the sample</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{PMID}|{DOI}|{URL}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>sample material processing</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_mat_process</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Processing applied to the sample during or after isolation</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text|term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample pooling</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_pooling</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Physical combination of several instances of like material, e.g., RNA extracted from samples or dishes of cell cultures into one big aliquot of cells. Please provide a short description of the samples that were pooled</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>biological sample replicate</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_rep_biol</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Measurements of biologically distinct samples that show biological variation</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>technical sample replicate</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_rep_tech</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Repeated measurements of the same sample that show independent measures of the noise associated with the equipment and the protocols</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>sample size</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_size</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Amount or size of sample (volume, mass or area) that was collected</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample source material category</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_source_mat_cat</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>This is the scientific role or category that the subject organism or material has with respect to an investigation. This field accepts terms listed under specimen source material category (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/GENEPIO_0001237 or http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/OBI_0100051)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample storage device</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_stor_device</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The container used to store the sample. This field accepts terms listed under container (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C43186). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the storage device</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample storage media</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_stor_media</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The liquid that is added to the sample collection device prior to sampling. If the sample is pre-hydrated, indicate the liquid media the sample is pre-hydrated with for storage purposes. This field accepts terms listed under microbiological culture medium (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/MICRO_0000067). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the sample storage media</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample storage duration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_store_dur</HarmonizedName>
      <Description/>
      <Format>
        <Description/>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample storage location</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_store_loc</HarmonizedName>
      <Description/>
      <Format>
        <Description/>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample storage temperature</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_store_temp</HarmonizedName>
      <Description/>
      <Format>
        <Description/>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample transport container</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_transport_cont</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Container in which the sample was stored during transport. Indicate the location name, e.g., bottle, cooler, glass vial, plastic vial, vendor supplied container</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample transport duration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_transport_dur</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>The duration of time from when the sample was collected until processed. Indicate the duration for which the sample was stored written in ISO 8601 format</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>sample transport temperature</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_transport_temp</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Temperature at which sample was transported, e.g., -20 or 4 degree Celsius</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit} {text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>sample volume or weight for DNA extraction</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>samp_vol_we_dna_ext</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>volume (mL) or weight (g) of sample processed for DNA extraction</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>serovar or serotype</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>serovar_or_serotype</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A characterization of a cell or microorganism based on the antigenic properties of the molecules on its surface. Indicate the name of a serovar or serotype of interest. This field accepts terms under organism (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C14250). This field also accepts identification numbers from NCBI under https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/taxonomy</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>size fraction selected</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>size_frac</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Filtering pore size used in sample preparation, e.g., 0-0.22 micrometer</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{term}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Nucleic Acid Sequence Source">
      <Name>source material identifiers</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>source_material_id</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>unique identifier assigned to a material sample used for extracting nucleic acids, and subsequent sequencing. The identifier can refer either to the original material collected or to any derived sub-samples.</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>antimicrobial phenotype of spike-in bacteria</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_amr</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Qualitative description of a microbial response to antimicrobial agents. Bacteria may be susceptible or resistant to a broad range of antibiotic drugs or drug classes, with several intermediate states or phases. This field accepts terms under antimicrobial phenotype (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/ARO_3004299)</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit};{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in with antibiotics</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_antibiotic</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Antimicrobials used in research study to assess effects of exposure on microbiome of a specific site. Please list antimicrobial, common name and/or class and concentration used for spike-in</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text} {integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in organism count</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_count</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Total cell count of any organism (or group of organisms) per gram, volume or area of sample, should include name of organism followed by count. The method that was used for the enumeration (e.g., qPCR, atp, mpn, etc.) should also be provided, e.g., total prokaryotes; 3.5e7 cells per ml; qPCR</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text};{float} {unit};[ATP|MPN|qPCR|other]</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in growth medium</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_growth_med</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A liquid or gel containing nutrients, salts, and other factors formulated to support the growth of microorganisms, cells, or plants (National Cancer Institute Thesaurus). A growth medium is a culture medium which has the disposition to encourage growth of particular bacteria to the exclusion of others in the same growth environment. In this case, list the culture medium used to propagate the spike-in bacteria during preparation of spike-in inoculum. This field accepts terms listed under microbiological culture medium (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/MICRO_0000067). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the spike in growth media</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in with heavy metals</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_metal</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Heavy metals used in research study to assess effects of exposure on microbiome of a specific site. Please list heavy metals and concentration used for spike-in</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text} {integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike in organism</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_org</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Taxonomic information about the spike-in organism(s). This field accepts terms under organism (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C14250). This field also accepts identification numbers from NCBI under https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/taxonomy. Multiple terms can be separated by pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in bacterial serovar or serotype</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_serovar</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Taxonomic information about the spike-in organism(s) at the serovar or serotype level. This field accepts terms under organism (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C14250). This field also accepts identification numbers from NCBI under https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/taxonomy. Multiple terms can be separated by pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>spike-in microbial strain</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>spikein_strain</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Taxonomic information about the spike-in organism(s) at the strain level. This field accepts terms under organism (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/NCIT_C14250). This field also accepts identification numbers from NCBI under https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/taxonomy. Multiple terms can be separated by pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{termLabel} {[termID]}|{integer}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>study design</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>study_design</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Epidemiological or omics reseach design context that this biosample was used in.</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description/>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>study incubation duration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>study_inc_dur</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Sample incubation duration if unpublished or unvalidated method is used. Indicate the timepoint written in ISO 8601 format</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>study incubation temperature</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>study_inc_temp</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Sample incubation temperature if unpublished or unvalidated method is used</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>time-course duration</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>study_timecourse</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>For time-course research studies involving samples of the food commodity, indicate the total duration of the time-course study</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>study treatment</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>study_tmnt</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>A process in which the act is intended to modify or alter some other material entity. From the study design, each treatment is comprised of one level of one or multiple factors. This field accepts terms listed under treatment (http://purl.obolibrary.org/obo/MCO_0000866). If the proper descriptor is not listed please use text to describe the study treatment. Multiple terms can be separated by one or more pipes</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{text}|{termLabel} {[termID]}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>temperature</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>temp</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>temperature of the sample at time of sampling</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float} {unit}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
    <Attribute use="optional" group_name="Food-animal and animal feed">
      <Name>timepoint</Name>
      <HarmonizedName>timepoint</HarmonizedName>
      <Description>Time point at which a sample or observation is made or taken from a biomaterial as measured from some reference point. Indicate the timepoint written in ISO 8601 format</Description>
      <Format>
        <Description>{float}</Description>
      </Format>
    </Attribute>
  </Package>
</BioSamplePackages>
